did you know that MIT has invested in
matrimony.com but can it give you good
returns let's find that out in this
video
[Music]
hi everyone welcome to stop talk with
Jay I'm your host jobsna and we are
going to analyze maximally.com today
let's understand maximly.com's business
and how it makes money matrimony.com
more commonly known by its brand name
Bharat matrimony is India's number one
online matchmaking software
what that means is you can go to their
app or website you can create an account
for yourself and then you can look for
prospective brides and rooms
matrimony.com has the highest market
share pan India at 60 it is a number one
online matchmaking company in India and
has an active user base of 50 lakh plus
users the company has been around for
around 22 years and it holds more than
300 crores in cash for itself
let's take a look at the brands owned by
the company Bharat matrimony is the most
popular brand with the famous cricketer
dhoni as the brand ambassador you must
have seen their advertisements With
viral campaigns like find your equal or
the ones targeted towards social
upliftment like
other brands include Community matrimony
which caters to matchmaking within a
community like Tamil Rajasthani or
Agarwal matrimony Indians prefer
marrying within their Community
especially if it's an arranged marriage
they also have special segments targeted
towards divorced prospects or LGBT
community
they also have the premium segment of
elite matrimony as well as the ones
targeted towards a specific set of
educational institutes like IID I am
Shadi more recently they launched their
portal called Jody which is targeted
towards non-graduates
in addition to the matchmaking business
which contributes 98 to their revenue
they also are into the marriage Services
business which makes up about two
percent of the revenue their portals
like monday.com and weddingbazaar.com
are respectively used for booking
wedding venues and to find wedding
vendors for catering decoration
Etc let's take a look at the Indian
wedding Market the population of India
is 1.4 billion people out of which 600
million are unmarried the median age of
India is 26.7 years where 100 million
plus are actively looking to get married
and they're around 11 to 13 million
weddings that happen every year in India
around 80 percent of marriages in India
are engaged and six percent are done via
online matchmaking marriage related
spends annually are 50 billion dollars
this is a pre-covered number and online
matchmaking revenue is expected to hit
260 Million by 2024. Additionally the
urbanization percentage of India is
expected to hit 37 to 38 by 2025 which
will lead to an increase in the number
of people who are looking for online
matchmaking so that is the Indian
wedding Market in general
let's look at the financials now the PE
or price to earning ratio of this talk
is 27.6 the debt to equity of the
company is 0.22 and in terms of prices
its current price is 623 rupees per
share if you take a look at the entire
year the highest price point was 1085
whereas the lowest price point was 576
rupees
let's take a look at the profit and loss
statement of the company over the last
decade
so till about 2016 the company was loss
making but after that it has turned
around last year it clocked down 434
crores of Revenue or income from sales
in terms of the net profit last year
they clocked in 54 crores as the net
profit after tax
let's take a look at their shareholding
pattern the promoters of the company own
around 50 stake in the company whereas
the public owns around 10 percent
rest of this rest of the shareholding is
by FIS mutual funds and aifs with FIS
holding around 25 equity in the company
to summarize matimney.com is the market
leader in online matchmaking segment in
India they have a healthy balance sheet
with Marquee investors and they use data
analytics to make business decisions
however please consult your financial
advisor before making any Investments as
this video is only for educational
purposes if you like this video give it
a thumbs up
And subscribe to the channel for all the
latest up dates and if you have any
thoughts comments or any additional
information that you would like to share
with all the viewers comment your
thoughts down below